Leopold Stokowski Papers, 1916-1994 PUSp.Ms. Coll. 381
University of Pennsylvania: Rare Book Manuscript Library
- Awards and artwork, VIII
  - Artwork, B
    - Moskowitz, H. S. Portrait of Leopold Stokowski, dry point etching, 25 x 20.5 cm., undated (Box 39, Folder 689)
    - Werner, Edna. Portrait of Leopold Stokowski, pencil, 30 x 22.5 cm., 1969 (Box 39, Folder 690)
    - Wolf, Ben. Portrait of Leopold Stokowski, line drawing, undated; 2 copies (Box 39, Folder 691)
    - Miscellaneous images, caricatures of Stokowski (Box 39, Folder 692)
      Includes a photocopy of Alfred Bendiner's caricature of Stokowski; and materials donated by Sol Schoenbach, including a caricature of Schoenbach and an Alfred Bendinder drawing of Hilberg, Kincaid, Caston.
    - Beauchamp, Reginald. Large caricature of Leopold Stokowski, marker and spray paint on fabric (Box 39)
  - Memorabilia, C
    - Organ roll, 1925 (Box 40)
      Recorded for the Duo-Art Aeolian Pipe Organ. Stokowski playing Bach's Passacaglia arr. Stokowski. Gift to Edward W. Box and Mary Louise Curtis Bok from Stokowski.
- Oversize, IX
  - Photographs. Oversize and miscellaneous photographs, A
    See also Drawer 61.
    - Stokowski and the Philadelphia Orchestra at John Wanamaker with Pietro Yon and Charles M. Courboin. Photo by Matthew Griendlerie [?], 1920; 6 copies (Box 41, Folder 693)
    - Leopold Stokowski, autographed portrait. Photo by E. Goldensky, Philadelphia, Pa., 1920s (Box 41, Folder 694)
    - Leopold Stokowski at the Bok family residence, inscribed for Miss Thompson; Stokowski on the Maine coast, 1920s (Box 41, Folder 695)
    - Sonya Stokowski, circa 1924 (Box 41, Folder 696)
    - Stokowski with the Curtis Student Orchestra, 1926-1927 (Box 41, Folder 697)
    - Stokowski with the All-American Youth Orchestra. Photos by Fred Hess Son, 1940-1941; 6 copies (Box 41, Folder 698)
    - Stokowski autographed portrait, inscribed to Boris Koutzen, undated (Box 41, Folder 699)
    - Audience at Pacific Coast Music Festival, 1955 (Box 41, Folder 700)
      Photo courtesy of Leighton Rollins, see correspondence in Ms. Coll. 382.
    - Stokowski conducting at the Edinburgh Music Festival. London Observer, 1961 (Box 41, Folder 701)
    - Stokowski at recording sessions in London, Photos by Michael Ward (Box 41, Folder 702)
    - Stokowski at his desk, 1067 5th Ave., New York, N.Y. Photos by Paul J. Hoeffler, 1971 (Box 41, Folder 703)
    - Walt Disney Productions. Black and white photographs from Fantasia, 1940 (Box 41, Folder 704)
    - Photographs of publicity materials, in Spanish, from the 1940 tour of the All-American Youth Orchestra (Box 41, Folder 705)
      Also includes items re Stokowski's 95th birthday and his obituary.
    - Curtis Institute of Music Stokowski Collection, circa 1980 (Box 41, Folder 706)
      Includes 1 photo of Edwin E. Heilakka, in color.
    - Photographs of Stokowski's scores, awards, a drawing by Stokowski, etc., undated (Box 41, Folder 707)
  - Clippings, 1906-1996; B
    Description Arrangement
    Newspaper clippings arranged chronologically. Includes photocopies of clippings and original materials.
    - Clippings, 1906-1916 (Box 42, Folder 708-709)
    - Clippings, 1916-1926 (Box 42, Folder 710-711)
      Re Stokowski, the Philadelphia Orchestra and the Wanamaker Organ, compiled by Ray Biswanger.
    - Clippings, 1924-1976 (Box 42, Folder 712-719)
    - Stokowski obituaries (Box 42, Folder 720-722)
    - Clippings, 1978-1996 (Box 42, Folder 723-732)
  - Awards and certificates, C
    - Academy of Musical Recorded Arts and Sciences honorary membership certificate, 1954 (Box 43, Folder 733)
    - Philadelphia Oarchestra Pension Foundation honorary life membership certificate, 1959-1960 (Box 43, Folder 734)
    - International Association of Concert Managers certificate (Box 43, Folder 735)
    - National Federation of Music Clubs citation, 1967 April 15 (Box 43, Folder 736)
    - Veterans Administration Voluntary Service certificate, 1969 May 12 (Box 43, Folder 737)
    - National Music Council citation, 1972 April 18 (Box 43, Folder 738)
    - American Composers Alliance Laurel Leaf Award, 1972 April 18 (Box 43, Folder 739)
    - Silhouettes in Courage certificate, 1972 (Box 43, Folder 740)
    - National Academy of Recording Arts and Sciences. Hall of Fame Award, for Bach-Stokowski Toccata and Fugue in D Minor (1927), 1978 (Box 43, Folder 741)
    - National Academy of Recording Arts and Sciences. Hall of Fame Award, for Rachmaninoff, Rhapsody on a Theme of Paganini, RCA Victor 1935 recording, 1979 (Box 43, Folder 742)
    - Help Hospitalized Veterans certificate, undated (Box 43, Folder 743)
    - Philadelphia, Pa., Office of the Mayor, Richardson Dilworth. Honorary Citizen Certificate, undated (Box 43, Folder 744)
  - Memorabilia, D
    - Oversize Memorabilia, 1
      - Sixtieth Anniversary Concert Program, cover photograph by Claude Picasso, undated (Box 43, Folder 745)
      - Philadelphia Orchestra Tour. Menu, 1936 May 19 (Box 43, Folder 746)
      - Leopold Stokowski RCA Victor Records Jacket autographed by Marian Anderson (Box 43, Folder 747)
      - Birthday Card to Leopold Stokowski from C. F. Peters Company, 1972 April 18 (Box 43, Folder 748)
      - U.S. postage stamps. Classical conductors and composers including Leopold Stokowski, sealed, undated (Box 43, Folder 749)
      - Deck plan for the cruise ship Italia, with Stokowski's staterooms marked in pencil, 1930s (Box 43, Folder 750)
      - Ball, Ronald H. Architect's drawings for shelving units at Nether Wallop for Leopold Stokowski (Box 43, Folder 751)
      - Leopold Stokowski's batons (Box 43)
    - Fantasia, 2
      - Walt Disney Productions. Souvenir program book for Fantasia, 1940; 2 copies (Box 44, Folder 752)
      - Fantasia, 1990 (Box 44, Folder 753)
        * Posters, 2 copies.
        * 50th anniversary glass plate and pin.
        * 50th anniversary reissue, videorecording, sealed
  - Oversize sculpture, E
    - Schweizer, J. Otto. Bronze relief portrait of Leopold Stokowski, 1923 (Box 45)
    - Jones, Charlotte Mercer. Plaster relief portrait of Leopold Stokowski, undated (Box 46)
  - Oversize musical instrument, F
    - Balalaika (Box 47)
  - Posters, G (Drawer 61)
    * American Symphony Orchestra, 1966-1967 season
    * Stokowski conducts the New Philharmonia, Royal Albert Hall, London, 14 May 1974
    * WFLN poster with drawing of Stokowski, undated [after 1977]
    * Curtis Institute of Music, Stokowski Centennial, conducted by Zubin Mehta, 18 April 1982
    * Fantasia posters located on poster shelving, Dietrich Storage Area. 2 items